craftsetc.com 2014-06-26

# Privacy Policy - Privacy Policy | Shop Hobby Lobby

**Hobby Lobby Stores, Inc.  
Privacy Policy**

This privacy policy (the "Policy") explains how information about you is collected, used, and disclosed by Hobby Lobby Stores, Inc. (“Hobby Lobby,” “we” or “us”) when you access or use our websites or other online or mobile services or applications (collectively the "Service"), sign up for our mailing list, and shop in our stores.

**Information We Collect**

_**Information You Provide to Us**_

: We collect any information that you submit to us voluntarily through the Service or provide to us in any other way. We collect information when you create an online account or profile; use the interactive areas and features of our Service; make an online or in-store purchase; request customer service; participate in contests, promotions, or mailing lists; and when you email, call, or otherwise communicate with us. For example, when you make a purchase through our Service, we may collect transaction information, such as your name, billing address, shipping address, payment information, phone number, and email address.

 _ **Information Collected Automatically**_

: We receive and store certain types of information automatically when you interact with our Service, emails, and online advertising. This information may included your IP address, browsing behavior while on our site, browser and device characteristics, referring URLs, the operating system you are using, and third party links, advertisements, and offers from our partners that you click on or other content that you may access or download from the Service.

 _ **Email**_

: When you email us, we are collecting the information you include in your email communication to us.

 _ **Cookies and Tracking Technologies**_

: We, and our third party vendors such as Google, use first-party cookies (such as Google Analytics), third-party cookies (such as Double-Click), and related tracking technologies to deliver and enhance the use of the Service, and inform, optimize, and serve ads based on your history with our websites.  We also use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to report how our ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits on our website.  A “cookie” is a small amount of data that gets installed on the hard drive of a user's computer serving as an anonymous unique identifier and allowing the website to recognize future visits from that user’s computer. We use tracking cookies to analyze user behavior on our Service. For example, the information provided through cookies is used to recognize you as a previous user, to offer personalized web page content and information for your use, and to otherwise facilitate your experience in connection with our Service. Most browsers automatically accept cookies as the default setting, but you may choose to decline cookies if your browser permits. Please be aware, however, that doing so may affect your use of the Service (such as impeding you from logging in to your account) and hampering your ability to access certain features of our Service.

We may use “web beacons” or “pixel tags” to compile tracking information related to our email campaigns. A “web beacon” or “pixel tag” is an electronic image, also called a "gif," that may be used on website pages to deliver cookies, count visits and compile statistics on usage and campaign effectiveness, or in our emails to tell us if an email has been opened and acted upon.

 _ **Interest-Based Advertising**_

: We may allow third party advertising networks to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. To do this, they will collect anonymous information about your visits to our site, which may include such things as age, gender, and interests, and your interaction with our Service. They may also use information about your visits to other websites to target advertisements. These targeted advertisements may appear on other sites that you visit. We also utilize remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online.  This anonymous information is collected through the use of a cookie, pixel tag, or similar technology. To learn more about interest-based ads, and how you may be able to opt out of such targeted advertising, please visit the Digital Advertising Alliance’s website at http://www.aboutads.info/choices/ or the Network Advertising Initiative website at http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices /.  

 _ **Display Advertising**_

.  We may utilize Google Analytics tools, including Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Double-Click Campaign Manager Integration, or Google Analytics Demographics and Impression Recording to support display advertising.

**How We Use Your Information**

Pursuant to the terms of this Policy, we may use the information we collect from you to:

•    provide and deliver products and services, process and complete transactions, and send you related information, including purchase confirmations, invoices, updates, security alerts, recall notices and support and administrative messages;  
•    investigate and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities;  
•    respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;  
•    communicate with you about Hobby Lobby and partner products, services, offers, promotions, news, upcoming events, and other information we think will be of interest to you;  
•    monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities;  
•    personalize the Service and provide advertisements, content, or features that are targeted toward your interests;  
•    process and deliver contest or sweepstakes entries and prizes; and  
•    provide, maintain, and improve the Service or our overall business.

**Sharing Your Information**

The information we collect is used to improve the content and the quality of our Service, and without your consent we will not otherwise sell, license or share your personal information to/with any other party(s) for commercial purposes, except: (a) to provide the Service, (b) when we have your permission, and/or (c) or under the following instances:

_**Affiliates:**_

We may share the information we collect with our subsidiaries and affiliates, for operational, marketing and promotional purposes.

 _ **Credit Card Provider:**_

We may share the information we collect with our banking partners, including U.S. Bancorp, which issues the Hobby Lobby Rewards Visa Card.

 _ **Service Providers:**_

We may share your information with our third-party service providers that support various aspects of our business operations (e.g., web hosting, storage, shipping, fulfillment, mobile marketing, analytics providers, call center service providers, sweepstakes vendors, and payment processors). When we do use an outside company, we use contractual or other appropriate means to ensure that personal information is used in a manner that is consistent with this Policy.

 _ **Legal Disclosure and Business Transfers:**_

We may disclose your information as permitted or required by law without your consent, if we are compelled to release information by a court of law or other person or entity with jurisdiction to compel production of such information (e.g., subpoenas). Additionally, if we have reasonable grounds to believe information could be useful in the investigation or prevention of improper or unlawful activity (i.e., suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our Terms of Use), we may disclose information voluntarily to law enforcement agencies or other appropriate investigative bodies without obtaining your consent before doing so.

Hobby Lobby may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including any information we collect from you, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization, change in control, or sale of assets or in the event of bankruptcy.

**Links to Third-Party Websites**

Our Service contains links to other websites. If you choose to visit an advertiser by "clicking on" a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third-party link, you will be directed to that third party's website. The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third-party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other websites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

**Social Media Sharing**

The Service may offer social sharing features or other integrated tools, which let you share actions you take on the Service with other media, and vice versa.  The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the third party that provides the social sharing feature. The fact that we link to or provide integrated tools for sharing with social media sites is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that social media site, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices.  For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the third parties that provide these features.

**Securing Your Personal Info**

Hobby Lobby endeavors to safeguard your personal information to ensure that such personal information is protected from loss, theft, unauthorized access, or disclosure. However, hardware or software failure, the inherent insecurity of the Internet and other factors, may compromise the security of your information at any time. Therefore we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information.

**Children and Minors**

The Service is not intended for use by minors under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly solicit any information from or market to such minors. If you are a parent or legal guardian who discovers that your child has provided us with information without your consent, please contact us.

**Changes**

We may periodically update this Policy at our sole discretion. We will post any changes to this Policy to our website, and if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, in some cases, email notification of such changes). Please ensure that your primary email address on file with us is correct. You can update or correct certain information through the Service. To do so, please visit the Hobby Lobby [email preference center](http://www.hobbylobby.com/email_subscriptions/subscribe.cfm), where you can access and modify your individual preferences and some of your personal information, or contact us by email by clicking here.

**Opting Out**

We may send you communications regarding our Service, including (without limitation): (a) notices about your use of our Service (including any notices regarding violations of such use), (b) updates to our Service, and (c) promotional information and materials related to our Service. You may opt out of receiving these promotional emails and other promotional communications from us at any time by visiting the Hobby Lobby [email preference center](http://www.hobbylobby.com/email_subscriptions/subscribe.cfm), and modifying your individual preferences or by contacting us with your specific request. Please note, however, that opt-out requests will not apply to non-promotional system messages (e.g., transactional service messages, security alerts, update notices).

**Contacting Us**

Please contact us with any questions, comments or concerns about this Policy.
